Guide to the Awards Reference collection, 1972-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Awards Reference collection 1972-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
0.7 linear feet Extent: 400 Items
The Awards Reference Collection contains files of clippings, flyers, lists, memoranda and other material concerning awards, prizes, medals, and similar marks of distinction.
UA.01.11.0013
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Awards Reference collection was compiled from various sources by University Archives staff for reference and research.
Collection Overview
The Awards Reference Collection contains files of clippings, flyers, lists, memoranda and other material concerning awards, prizes, medals, and other marks of distinction awarded by the University or by other organizations to members of the University community. Information spans the period from 1879 to the present. This collection does not include information about scholarships; see the Scholarships Reference Collection. Information about the awards listed here and also other awards can also be found in the records of the President and other administrative officers, and in the records of departments and schools. See, for example, the English Department records for information about The Anne Flexner Memorial Award for Creative Writing, or the Personnel Office Reference Collection for information about awards made to employees.
Subject Headings
College teachers -- Awards -- North Carolina -- Durham; Duke University -- Prizes; Duke University -- Founders’ Day; Nobel Prizes
Related Material
Founders' Day Collection.
Duke University Archives
Personnel Office Reference Collection.
Duke University Archives
Scholarships Reference Collection.
Duke University Archives
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Awards - general (Box 1)
  - Awards - lists from commencement programs, 1984-1993 (Box 1)
  - Awards Convocation, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award, 1951-[1964], 2003- (Box 1)
  - Alumni Distinguished Undergraduate Teaching Awards, 1970/71- (Box 1)
  - Anne McDougall Memorial Award, 1986/87- (Box 1)
  - Bascom Headen Palmer Literary Prize, 1991- (Box 1)
  - Benenson Awards in the Arts, 1983- (Box 1)
  - Blue Devil Award, 1982- (Box 1)
  - Braxton Craven Medal, [1884-?] (Box 1)
  - Charles A. Dukes Awards for Outstanding Volunteer Service, 1983- (Box 1)
  - Distinguished Alumni Award, 1983- (Box 1)
  - Hal Kammerer Memorial Awards for Film and Video Production, 1989- (Box 1)
  - Howard Johnson Distinguished Teaching Award, 1988- (Box 1)
  - Humanitarian Service Award, 1984/85- (Box 1)
  - James R. Sheffield Award, [1966-?] (Box 1)
  - Karl Menger Award in Mathematics, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Lars Lyon Volunteer Service Award, 1990- (Box 1)
  - Louis Sudler Prize, 1983- (Box 1)
  - Marcus E. Hobbs Service Award, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Nobel Prizes (Box 1)
  - Presidential Award, 1984- (Box 1)
  - Richard K. Lublin Distinguished Award for Teaching Excellence, 1992- (Box 1)
  - Robert and Ray Kroc Research Award, 1987- (Box 1)
  - Rosati Awards in Creative Writing, 1990- (Box 1)
  - Time College Achievement Awards, [1986?] (Box 1)
  - Trinity College Distinguished Teaching Awards, 1983/84- (Box 1)
  - University Medal for Distinguished Meritorious Service, 1986- (Box 1)
  - University Scholar/Teacher of the Year Award, 1982- (Box 1)
  - Wakeman Award, 1982, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Wiley Grey Medal, 1879- (Box 1)
  - William J. Griffith University Service Award, 1991/92- (Box 1)
  - Willis Smith Prize, 1932- (Box 1)